Guide to the Gail and Stephen Rudin American presidential collection, 1775-2009.
Rudin, Gail and Stephen American presidential collection
- Series II. Other U.S. presidents
  - Clinton, William Office held: As President Writer's location: Washington, D.C., January 25, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    Senate Pass for Impeachment Proceedings.
    Rudin # P-40
  - Clinton, William, February 13, 1999; Newspaper (Box 13, Folder 9)
    New York Times coverage of Clinton acquittal.
  - Coolidge, Calvin Office held: As Governor of Massachusetts Writer's location: "Executive Chamber Boston, MA", September 24, 1919; Pages: 1 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Response to the Boston Police Strike.
    Rudin # P-41
  - Coolidge, Calvin Office held: As Governor of Massachusetts Addressee: "Wendell P. Stafford, Justice - Supreme Court, District of Columbia" Writer's location: State House, Boston, March 10, 1920; Pages: 1 1/4 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    The law and his handling of strikes. "The real remedy for strikes will be the conviction that they do not pay".
    Rudin # P-42
  - Coolidge, Calvin Office held: As the new President Writer's location: Washington, D.C., August 4, 1923; Pages: 1 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    His first official proclamation as President declaring a day of mourning for Harding. From the Forbes Collection - Part 2.
    Rudin # P-43
  - Coolidge, Calvin Office held: As President Addressee: Delegates of the Boy Scouts of America Writer's location: Washington, D.C., July 26, 1924; Pages: 1 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Speech discussing the three fundamentals of Scouting.
    Rudin # P-44
  - Coolidge, Calvin Office held: As President Writer's location: Washington, D.C., December 31, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    Presidential Pay Check.
    Rudin # P-45
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D. Office held: As Commander-in-Chief Addressee: Mamie Eisenhower Writer's location: Algiers, March 31, 1943; Pages: 1 3/4 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    Loving letter to his wife, Mamie.
    Rudin # P-46
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D. Office held: As Supreme NATO Commander Addressee: "Clifford R. Hope, Congressman" Writer's location: Supreme Hdqtrs Allied Powers, Europe, March 8, 1952; Pages: 2 1/2 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Considerations for the 1952 Presidential campaign. From the Forbes Collection - Part 4.
    Rudin # P-47
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D. Office held: As President Addressee: "Robert P. Skinner, Ambassador (Retired)" Writer's location: "The White House Washington, D.C.", March 27, 1953; Pages: 1 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Discusses activities of Voice of America abroad.
    Rudin # P-48
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D. Office held: As President Addressee: Francis Case, Senator Writer's location: "The White House Washington, D.C.", September 29, 1953; Pages: 1 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Regarding government spending.
    Rudin # P-49
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D. Office held: As President Addressee: Richard L. Tobin Writer's location: Gettysburg, PA, July 17, 1962; Pages: 2, 2 photographs, envelope (Box 4, Folder 3a)
    Eisenhower speaks out on the powers of the presidency. With original envelope. Both letter and envelope are marked PERSONAL.
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D. Office held: As ex-President Addressee: Earl Mazo Writer's location: Gettysburg, PA, August 27, 1965; Pages: 1 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    "Comments on the Bay of Pigs, Guatemala and his view of the presidency." Included is Mazo's TLS to Eisenhower dated 8/25/1965.
    Rudin # P-51
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D. Office held: As ex-President Addressee: "Tom H. Parks" Writer's location: Gettysburg, PA, July 5, 1966; Pages: 1 1/2 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    "A discussion of our national morals." With Free Franked Envelope.
    Rudin # P-52
  - Fillmore, Millard Office held: As Comptroller of New York State Addressee: Hiram C. Day Writer's location: Albany, NY, June 9, 1848; Pages: 1 1/4 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Having just heard of his nomination for Vice President on the 1848 ticket of Taylor/Fillmore. Included is a one page letter dated 5/8/1890 from Hiram Day sending this letter to a Rev. Charles C. Pierce who had requested a Fillmore autograph.
    Rudin # P-53
  - Fillmore, Millard Office held: As Whig candidate for Vice President Addressee: Joshua R. Giddings Writer's location: Albany, NY, July 7, 1848; Pages: 1 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Concedes the right of the public to examine and criticize his past political conduct.
    Rudin # P-54
  - Fillmore, Millard Office held: As ex-President Addressee: Lydia H. Sigourney, Poet Writer's location: Buffalo, NY, January 1, 1860 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Free Franked Envelope.
    Rudin # P-55
  - Fillmore, Millard Office held: As ex-President Addressee: Baltimore political committee Writer's location: Buffalo, NY, October 20, 1860; Pages: 2 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Gives his reasons for not speaking at a rally for Bell & Everett but he will give them his vote.
    Rudin # P-56
  - Ford, Gerald, 2006, 2007; Stamps (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Ford memorial envelopes, sheet of 41-cent stamps, first day of issue envelope with 41-cent Ford stamp.
  - Ford, Gerald Office held: As Congressman Addressee: Thomas E. Goertner Writer's location: Congress, Washington, D.C., February 7, 1967; Pages: 1 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    "Concerning Communist teaching in New York schools." With Free Franked Envelope.
    Rudin # P-57
  - Ford, Gerald Office held: As Congressman Addressee: Ed Hornburg Writer's location: Congress, Washington, D.C., April 20, 1970; Pages: 1 1/3 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    On impeaching Justice Douglas, postal rates, space exploration, and corruption among high government officials ("even high officers...are subject to prosecution when they violate their trust").
    Rudin # P-58
  - Ford, Gerald Office held: As Congressman Addressee: Ms. Joyce Veneklase Writer's location: Congress, Washington, D.C., February 5, 1973; Pages: 1 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    Comments on abortion.
    Rudin # P-59
  - Ford, Gerald Office held: As President Addressee: Press Release Writer's location: "The White House Washington, D.C.", May 15, 1975; Pages: 1 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    S.S. Mayaguez Affair.
    Rudin # P-60
  - Ford, Gerald Office held: As President Addressee: Henry Bellmon, Senator Writer's location: "The White House Washington, D.C.", February 21, 1976; Pages: 1 1/2 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Outlines his economic policies and his budget proposals.
    Rudin # P-61
  - Ford, Gerald, 1979
    "A Time To Heal" Harper and Row, New York, NY, Signed copy. See separated material below.
    Rudin # P-62
  - Ford, Gerald Office held: As ex-President Addressee: Neil Bogart, March 27, 1980; Pages: 1 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Discusses the possibility of a candidacy for President.
    Rudin # P-63
  - Ford, Gerald Office held: As ex-President Writer's location:, February 3, 1997; Pages: 1 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Warren Commission conclusions.
    Rudin # P-64
  - Ford, Gerald, 2006; Newspaper (Box 20)
    The New York Times reporting Ford's death.
  - Garfield, James Office held: As Congressman Addressee: Mr. E.B. Taylor Writer's location: Washington. D.C., December 22, 1863; Pages: 3 1/2 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Expresses sympathy for a friend's financial difficulties and offers a loan. Talks about the loss of his child. Tells of his first term in Congress.
    Rudin # P-65
  - Garfield, James Office held: As Congressman Addressee: Mr. A.B. Newburgh, Secy Bd of Public Works, Columbus, Ohio Writer's location: Washington, D.C., October 25, 1871; Pages: 1 1/4 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    He is grateful to receive examples of his father's handwriting.
    Rudin # P-66
  - Garfield, James Office held: As U.S. Representative from Ohio Addressee: Mrs. John A. Dahlgren Writer's location: Washington, D.C., June 11, 1872; Pages: 3 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    Assails the influence of money in politics.
    Rudin # P-67
  - Garfield, James Office held: As U.S. Senator and Presidential Candidate Addressee: "John D. Long, Governor of Massachusetts" Writer's location: Mentor, Ohio, June 15, 1880; Pages: 1 1/4 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    "The nomination was unsought and unexpected".
    Rudin # P-68
  - Garfield, James Office held: As President Writer's location: Long Branch, September 20, 1881; Pages: 1 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    "President Garfield Dead" Broadside.
    Rudin # P-69
  - Grant, Ulysses S. Office held: As President Writer's location: Washington, D.C., June 10, 1872; Pages: 2, framed (Box 12, Folder 10)
    Convenes the Congress to consider pressing matters. Original proclamation.
    Rudin # P-70
  - Grant, Ulysses S. Office held: As ex-President Addressee: H.A. Mumard? Writer's location: Galina, IL, August 31, 1880; Pages: 1 1/4 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Calls for universal suffrage.
    Rudin # P-71
  - Harding, Warren Office held: No elective office held Addressee:, December 30, 1908; Pages: 17 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    Handwritten speech manuscript about the ethics of bankers and the need for regulations.
  - Harding, Warren Office held: No elective office held Addressee: Mrs. J.F. Dunbaugh Writer's location: Frankfurt, Germany, April 1, 1909; Pages: 1 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    Humorous comment on his European church visits.
    Rudin # P-72
  - Harding, Warren Office held: As U.S. Senator Addressee: Howard N. Bible Writer's location: Washington, D.C., August 25, 1917; Pages: 1 1/4 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    Discusses Presidential war authority.
    Rudin # P-73
  - Harding, Warren Office held: As Presidential candidate Addressee: Dr. H.M. Dunlap Writer's location: Marion, Ohio, July 6, 1920; Pages: 1 1/2 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    Maps out the "front porch" strategy for his 1920 Presidential run. From the Forbes Collection Part 4.
    Rudin # P-74
  - Harding, Warren Office held: As President Addressee: Mrs. Harriet Taylor Upton, Republican National Committee Writer's location: Washington, D.C., May 26, 1922; Pages: 1 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    Harding is politely chauvinistic in considering a woman to head the Dept. of Welfare.
    Rudin # P-75
  - Harding, Warren Office held: President Addressee: Harry Wilson Walker Writer's location: Washington, D.C., March 5, 1923; Pages: 1 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    Defends his choice of Harry New as Postmaster General.
    Rudin # P-76
  - Harding, Warren Office held: As deceased President Writer's location: Washington, D.C., August 3, 1923; Pages: 1 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    Navy Department General Orders No. 111 announcing the death of Harding and the appointment of Calvin Coolidge as resident.
    Rudin # P-77
  - Harrison, Benjamin Office held: President-Elect Addressee: Senator John Sherman Writer's location: Indianapolis, IN, February 2, 1889; Pages: 2 1/2 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    Harrison struggles to fill his Cabinet posts with the right men. Included is a TLS in answer from Senator Sherman.
    Rudin # P-78
  - Harrison, Benjamin Office held: As President Addressee: Gov. McKinley and Gentlemen of the Committee Writer's location: Washington or Indianapolis?, June 1892; Pages: 7 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    Incumbent Harrison accepts the Republican Presidential nomination. From the Forbes Collection Part 3.
    Rudin # P-79
  - Harrison, Benjamin Office held: As President Writer's location: Washington, D.C., July 29, 1892; Pages: 1 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    Delineation of U.S. boundary with Canada.
    Rudin # P-80
  - Harrison, William H. Office held: As Governor of Indiana Territory Addressee: Col. James Henry Writer's location: Vincennes, April 26, 1805; Pages: 2 3/4 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    Harrison prepares to acquire massive land holdings in Indiana Territory.
    Rudin # P-81
  - Harrison, William H. Office held: As Senator - Chairman of Senate Committee on Military Affairs Addressee: James Barbour, Secy of War Writer's location: Washington, D.C., December 2, 1825; Pages: 1 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    Concerning unclaimed bounty lands due officers and soldiers of the Revolutionary War.
    Rudin # P-82
  - Hayes, Rutherford B. Office held: As Presidential candidate Writer's location: House of Representatives, February 1, 1877; Pages: 1 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Counting of the vote for President and Vice President.
    Rudin # P-83
  - Hayes, Rutherford B. Office held: As President Writer's location: Washington, D.C., June 12, 1879; Pages: 1 1/2 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Presidential pardon for a man convicted of manslaughter. Countersigned by William M. Everts, Secretary of State.
    Rudin # P-84
  - Hayes, Rutherford B. Office held: As ex-President Addressee: William Clark Writer's location: Fremont, Ohio, August 8, 1892; Pages: 1 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Discusses his activities during his retirement.
    Rudin # P-85
  - Hoover, Herbert Office held: As Chairman of American Relief Administration Addressee: Kent Perkins, Director of Publicity for Mass. Writer's location: New York, NY, June 25, 1920; Pages: 1 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Hoover says it is an honor to be thought of as a possible President. Outlines his political philosophy.
    Rudin # P-86
  - Hoover, Herbert Office held: As President Addressee: "Dr. Richard L. Weil, University of Wisconsin" Writer's location: Washington, D.C., November 6, 1930; Pages: 1 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Presidential Proclamation of Thanksgiving Day. Also included is a Hoover medallion.
    Rudin # P-87
  - Hoover, Herbert Office held: As President Writer's location: Washington, D.C., January 5, 1933; Pages: 1 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    Proclamation announcing the death of Calvin Coolidge. Countersigned by Henry Stimson, Secretary of State.
    Rudin # P-88
  - Hoover, Herbert Office held: As ex-President Addressee: Henry L. Stoddard Writer's location:, April 28, 1933; Pages: 1 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Reacts eight weeks after surrendering The White House to FDR.
    Rudin # P-89
  - Hoover, Herbert Office held: As ex-President Addressee: "Wheeler McMillen,Editor of The Farm Journal" Writer's location: The Waldorf Astoria, NY, November 5, 1942; Pages: 7 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    States his views in support of a food administrator during WWII, preferably the Secretary of Agriculture. Includes Hoover cover letter, Hoover statement, and statement, "The Importance of Food in this War" from H.B. Frese to Mr. Pate.
    Rudin # P-90
  - Hoover, Herbert Office held: As ex-President Writer's location: The Waldorf Astoria, NY, February 9, 1950; Pages: 3 1/2. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Reading copy of speech given when receiving the Moles Award. "The Moles 10th Annual Award Dinner".
    Rudin # P-91
  - Jackson, Andrew Office held: As Major General Addressee: Samuel Justice Writer's location: Fort Jackson, July 26, 1814; Pages: 1 1/4 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Remitting the death sentence on a deserter.
    Rudin # P-92
  - Jackson, Andrew Office held: As Major General Addressee: Samuel Carswell Writer's location: Nashville, TN, February 23, 1817; Pages: 1 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Regarding his nephew's admission to West Point.
    Rudin # P-92A
  - Jefferson, Thomas, 1954, 1968, 1976; Stamps (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Two commemorative envelopes with 6 first day of issue 1-cent stamps, one commemorative envelope with four 2-cent stamps, one envelope with four 13-cent stamps.
  - Jefferson, Thomas Office held: As Secretary of State Writer's location: New York, NY, August 2, 1790; Pages: 1, framed (Box 5, Folder 10A)
    Act of Congress pertaining to the procuring of seals for the Court system.
    Rudin # P-93
  - Johnson, Andrew Office held: As President Writer's location: Washington, D.C., May 8, 1866; Pages: 1, framed (Box 21)
    Commissioning Edward D. Townsend as Brevet Major General.
    Rudin # P-94
  - Johnson, Andrew Office held: As President Writer's location: Washington, D.C., April 11, 1868; Pages: 1, framed (Box 14)
    Impeachment Ticket.
    Rudin # P-95
  - Johnson, Andrew, 1868; Newspaper (Box 11)
    New York Times paper on impeachment acquittal.
  - Johnson, Lyndon Office held: As Senate Majority Leader Addressee: "Robert K. Pepper - News Editor, Fort Meyers News Press" Writer's location: Washington, D.C., July 22, 1957; Pages: 2 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Discusses how to handle Russia. See Nixon letter of 5/14/57 also written to Pepper.
    Rudin # P-96
  - Johnson, Lyndon Office held: As Senator Addressee: H. Lane Chandler Writer's location: Washington, D.C., September 1, 1959; Pages: 1 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Explains what America means to him.
    Rudin # P-97
  - Johnson, Lyndon Office held: As President Addressee: "James Roosevelt, House of Representatives" Writer's location: "The White House Washington, D.C.", 1960-1965; Pages: 1 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    The issue of equal rights for African Americans.
    Rudin # P-98
  - Johnson, Lyndon Office held: As Senate Democratic Leader Addressee: James Roosevelt Writer's location: Washington, D.C., November 17, 1960; Pages: 1 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Grateful for your warm message. (Johnson had just won the Vice Presidency under Kennedy).
    Rudin # P-101
  - Johnson, Lyndon Office held: As President Addressee: James Roosevelt Writer's location: "The White House Washington, D.C.", December 1963; Pages: 1 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Birthday Congratulations to Roosevelt.
    Rudin # P-100
  - Johnson, Lyndon Office held: As President Addressee: James Roosevelt Writer's location: "The White House Washington, D.C.", Oct. 1964; Pages: 1 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Election campaign letter. (Johnson is running for President).
    Rudin # P-99
  - Johnson, Lyndon Office held: As President Addressee: James Roosevelt Writer's location: "The White House Washington, D.C.", No Date; Pages: 1 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Thanks Roosevelt for his birthday greeting.
    Rudin # P-102
  - Johnson, Lyndon Office held: As President Addressee: "Eugene G. Mattison Jr., Administrative Director, Plans for Progress" Writer's location: "The White House Washington, D.C.", December 16, 1966; Pages: 1 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Discusses "providing equal opportunity for all our citizens".
    Rudin # P-103
  - Johnson, Lyndon Office held: As President Addressee: Cornelius Vanderbilt Jr. Writer's location: "The White House Washington, D.C.", June 19, 1967; Pages: 1 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Regarding nomination of Thurgood Marshall to the Supreme Court.
    Rudin # P-104
  - Kennedy, John F., 1961, 1964, 1967; Stamps (Box 5, Folder 16)
    JFK "Life in Stamps" envelopes and stamps, photograph with 5 cent stamp, inauguration envelope and stamp.
  - Kennedy, John F. Office held: As Senator Addressee: Mr. C.P. Cronk Writer's location: Washington, D.C., February 1, 1954; Pages: 1 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    Concerning the Bricker Resolution and congressional salaries.
    Rudin # P-105
  - Kennedy, John F. Office held: As Senator Addressee: "Mrs. A.E. Cassidy, Chairman Mass. State Fed. of Women's Clubs" Writer's location: "U.S. Senate Washington, D.C.", February 21, 1957; Pages: 1 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    "I most emphatically favor non-discriminatory treatment of women".
    Rudin # P-105A
  - Kennedy, John F. Office held: As Senator Addressee: Arthur Krock, N.Y. Times and William E. Dugan Writer's location: "U.S. Senate Washington, D.C.", July 31, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    Discussing his stands and those of his father. See also Bishop Fulton Sheen letter to William E. Dugan in collection #6875.
    Rudin # P-105B
  - "Kennedy, John F. (Janet Travell, M.D.)" Office held: As Senator Addressee: Dr. Janet Travell to Robert F. Kennedy Writer's location:, July 11, 1960; Pages: 1 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    Re: John F. Kennedy's health.
    Rudin # P-106
  - Kennedy, John F. Office held: As President Writer's location: Washington, D.C., January 21, 1961; Pages: 3 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    President Kennedy's schedule of appointments during his first day in office.
    Rudin # P-107
  - Kennedy, John F. (Janet Travell, M.D.) Office held: As President Addressee: "Leonard Lyons, New York Post" Writer's location: "The White House Washington, D.C.", October 11, 1961; Pages: 1 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    Reacting to the market for his signature.
    Rudin # P-108
  - Kennedy, John F. Office held: As President Addressee: Speaker of the House of Representatives Writer's location: "The White House Washington, D.C.", April 11, 1963; Pages: 1 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    Amendment to the budget (for foreign assistance) for fiscal year 1964.
    Rudin # P-109
  - Kennedy, John F., November 22-25, 1963; 9 sheets of various lengths, approx 8 1/2" wide by approx 99" in total length 66 apx. 8 1/2" x 11" photos (Box 19, Folder 5, 6)
    Original Associated Press Teletypes. Mainly of the events of Nov. 24, 1963. Photos show events from Nov. 22 to Nov. 25, 1963.
    Rudin # P-110
  - Kennedy, John F., November 22-25, 1963; 100 pages, various sizes (Box 19, Folder 4)
    Original Associated Press Teletypes. Mainly of the events of Nov. 22 (Friday), Nov. 23 (Saturday) and Nov. 25 (Monday), 1963.
    Rudin # P-111
  - Kennedy, John F., November 1963; 9 rolls (Box 16)
    Original Teletype rolls, regarding the assassination.
    Rudin # P-112
  - Kennedy, John F., November 1963; 30+ pages, 2 photos (Box 19, Folder 3)
    Original UPI/AP Teletypes. Received on teletype machines of the Santa Barbara News-Press. Together with two original AP wire photos as received by the Santa Barbara News-Press.
    Rudin # P-113
  - Kennedy, John F., November 1963; 32 pages, various sizes, (Box 19, Folder 2)
    Original AP Teletypes regarding the assassination.
    Rudin # P-114
  - Kennedy, John F., November 1963; 40 pages, various sizes (Box 19, Folder 1)
    Rudin # P-115
  - Kennedy, John F., November 22, 1963; 8 rolls, apx. 100 ft +, 12 individual "tear off" sheets - (Box 17)
    Original UPI Teletypes, the entire day of the assassination is chronicled.
    Rudin # P-116
  - Kennedy, John F., November 23-26, 1963; 1964; 6 newspapers (Box 11)
    6 copies of the New York Times and one copy of the Dallas Times Herald covering the assassination.
  - Madison, James Office held: As Secretary of State Addressee: Governor of Massachusetts Writer's location: Washington, D.C., September 24, 1804; Pages: 1, framed (Box 5, Folder 23A)
    Announcement of the passage of the Twelfth Amendment to the Constitution.
    Rudin # P-117
  - Madison, James Office held: As President - Also signed by Robert Smith, Secy of State and Caesar Rodney, Atty General Writer's location: Washington, D.C., April 20, 1810; Pages: 1 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    Patent for an early form of carbon paper.
    Rudin # P-118
  - Madison, James Office held: As President Also signed by James Monroe, Secy of State Addressee: Writer's location: Washington, D.C., June 15, 1815; Pages: 1, framed (Box 5, Folder 23B)
    Ship's passport for the Brig Calypso of Boston. See also Tyler for Sea Letter.
    Rudin # P-119
  - McKinley, William Office held: As Congressman Addressee: Mr. J.N. Taylor Writer's location: Washington, D.C., July 18, 1890; Pages: 1 1/4 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    Writes concerning the upcoming campaign.
    Rudin # P-120
  - McKinley, William Office held: As Governor of Ohio Addressee: "John D. Long, Governor of Massachusetts" Writer's location: Canton, Ohio, January 25, 1896; Pages: 1 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    McKinley working on forming his Cabinet almost ten months before being elected.
    Rudin # P-121
  - McKinley, William Office held: As President Addressee: "Honorable C.K. Davis, U.S. Senator" Writer's location: "Executive Mansion Washington, D.C. ", ca. 1898; Pages: 1 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    Soliciting Davis to be a member of Paris Peace Commission to end Spanish American War.
    Rudin # P-122
  - McKinley, William, September 1901; Newspapers (Box 9, Folder 1)
    New York Tribune and The Franklin Sentinel coverage of assassination of McKinley.
  - McKinley, William, September 14, 1901; Newspaper (Box 11)
    The Sun coverage of McKinley's death.
  - Monroe, James Office held: As Secy of State Writer's location: Washington, D.C., June 26, 1812; Pages: 3 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    Privateer Agreement for the ship "Union of Philadelphia".
    Rudin # P-123